we've been given
three pieces of code and we need to
determine what each piece of code is
going to print to the screen
so i've pasted up the first piece of
code that we've been given
and this code uses a ternary operator
if the expression that we provide the
operator evaluates as true
then the code on the left side of the
colon
will be executed if the condition that
we've provided evaluates as
false then the code on the right side of
the colon will be executed
so the condition we've provided our
ternary operator is a comparison
the string 4 is equal to the integer 4.
comparing a string to an integer for
equality is always going to return
false so we expect that ruby will
execute the code on the right side of
the colon
in this case we're invoking put us
and passing it the string false so we
expect to output
false let's run our code
and we see the output false
i'll paste in our next snippet of code
a local variable x has been initialized
and set to reference the integer 2.
below that we have an if statement the
condition we provide to this
if statement is comparing the equality
of the result of two different
arithmetic operations
so in our first expression here on the
left side we're multiplying 2 times 3
which will return 6 and then dividing
that by 2
which results in the integer three on
the right side
we add four and four to get eight
subtract
two to get six and subtract three which
will equal three
so this comparison that we have provided
as a condition to our if statement
is 3 is equal to 3 and this will return
true
so we expect that the code in this first
branch of our if statement will be
executed on line 3.
this code outputs the string did you get
it right
and let's run our code to see this
i'll paste in our third snippet of code
we have two local variables initialized
on lines 1
and 2 y references 9 and
x references 10. so let's check out our
if statement
the first condition we provide our if
statement on line 3
compares whether x plus 1 which will
evaluate to
11 is less than or equal to y which
references
9. so this condition evaluates to false
ruby will move on to line 5. this
condition evaluates whether x
plus 1 which evaluates to 11
is greater than or equal to y which
references 9.
since 11 is greater than 9 line
6 of our code will be executed we'll run
our code one more time to see that